Finding Aid for the Walter Gabrielson papers LSC.1830
UCLA Library Special Collections
Walter Gabrielson papers
1962-2008
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gabrielson, Walter
LSC.1830
42 Linear Feet (84 boxes, 2 oversize boxes)
Walter Gabrielson (1935-2008) was a southern California painter, sculptor, professor, and arts writer. He served as professor at California State University Northridge (1966-1981) and helped form the Los Angeles Institute of Contemporary Art (1973-1988). The collection consists of professional records and writings as well as preparatory drawings, visual reference materials and documentation of his artwork.
84 document boxes (42 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Nancy Goldberg, December 3, 2008.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9964950623606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Biography
Walter Gabrielson was born in Orr, Minnesota in 1935 and moved to Inglewood, California with his family in 1953. Gabrielson attended both Chouinard Art Institute and then transferred to the Otis Art Institute receiving his M.F.A in 1965. While still at Otis, Gabrielson worked as a printmaker for the Fantasmagoric Print Workshop and later for the Tamarind Institute. In the fall of 1966, Gabrielson began serving as a professor of art at California State University, Northridge and continued until 1981. During this time he participated actively in the local and national arts community. Most notably he was part of the founding committee of the Los Angeles Institute of Contemporary Art where he served as publications chairman. In 1974, he worked with Ed Wortz to lead an influential seminar through the UCLA extension program focusing on "The Ironic Los Angeles Artist," which included participation from John Baldessari, Ed Ruscha, Terry Allen, Karen Carson and many others.
Gabrielson exhibited his work throughout his life, including one-man and group shows in the Southern California area, as well as nationally and internationally. Notable exhibitions include a two-man show with James Turrell at the ARCO Art Center in 1976, "Decade, Los Angeles Painting in the Seventies" at the Art Center School of Design in 1981, and the "Collection of Michael Blankfort" exhibition at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art in 1982. Gabrielson had an ongoing relationship with the Contemporary Arts Forum of Santa Barbara, California, until his death in November 2008.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of drawings, photographs, and slides of Gabrielson's work as well as exhibition announcements, exhibition reviews and written works. A large portion of the collection is made of clippings and visual materials Gabrielson used as visual reference. The collection spans Gabrielson's artistic development with the inclusion of slides from early graduate work to drawings created in 2008. Images from various interactions with other local artists are included as well.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is organized by item type at the series level and by work or artistic project within series when applicable. The series are as follows:
Professional documentation, 1962-2008 (boxes 1-3)
Writings and books, ca. 1975-2004 (boxes 3-7, 85)
Artwork, ca. 1975-2008 (boxes 7-32, 84-86)
Sketchbooks, 1976-2007 (boxes 32-37)
Slides and photographs of work, 1962-2008 (boxes 37-46)
Research morgue, ca. 1962-2008 (boxes 47-83)
Related Material
Gabrielson, W., Persistence: My Life as an artist. Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institute, Washington, D.C., 1993.
Gabrielson, Walter
- 1. Professional Documentation, ca. 1970-2006
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes materials related to Gabrielson's professional life as artist, professor, critic, and curator including teaching materials, exhibition lists and reviews. Includes images and ephemera from the "Ironic Artist Los Angeles Artist" Seminar.
  - Curriculum vitae materials, ca. 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appearances in publications, 1970-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reviews of curated exhibition, "Addictions", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes for biographical statement revision, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Biographical notes
  - Revisions and updates to curriculum vitae, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes "publications featured in and authored by" list
  - Gabrielson, Walter and Peter Plagens. "Art Stripped Bare." Art and Auction vol. 21 no. 8 (1998-99): 60-63. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Copies of reviews of Gabrielson's exhibited work, 1970-2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Also includes copies of artist statements, copy of unpublished Peter Plagens article
  - Reifer, Susan. "Off Duty" In Style, March, 1998., 1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Gabrielson painting featured in article
  - Biographies and resumes for galleries, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Bakersfield Californian reviews, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Teaching statement, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Proofs of reviews about Gabrielson's work and drafts of artist statements, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Public service documentation, 1981-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Selected exhibitions lists, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reviews of Gabrielson's exhibited work, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Includes a detailed artist statement and explanation of some works
  - Raw data for resume, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Consists of press releases, grant applications, additional resume materials
  - Featured in publications -- drafts and revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - In the collection of -- drafts and revisions, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Former students, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Includes letter from former student
  - Beginning painting teaching materials, ca. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Beginning drawing teaching materials (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Includes course outline and assignments
  - Beginning drawing teaching materials (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Includes full syllabus and color study notes
  - Claremont teaching records, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Exhibition announcement cards (folder 1 of 3), 1980-2005 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Exhibition announcement cards (folder 2 of 3), 1978 -2002 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition announcement cards (folder 3 of 3), 1977-2001 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Includes announcement for "Addictions" exhibition curated by Gabrielson
  - Gallery publications featuring Gabrielson, 1982-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letters of recommendation, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Includes letters to the selective service board
  - Notes on teaching, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Work of former students (folder 1 of 4), 1973-2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Contains various materials documenting the artistic careers of students including exhibition cards and reviews.
  - Work of former students (folder 2 of 4), 1979-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Work of former students (folder 3 of 4), 1973-ca. 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Work of former students (folder 4 of 4), 1973-1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Gabrielson, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Art Center College of Design seminars -- preparatory work and materials (folder 1 of 3), ca. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Art Center College of Design seminars -- preparatory work and materials (folder 2 of 3), ca. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes syllabus for "Art, Creativity, and Consciousness" and outline for "Survival Strategies"
  - Art Center College of Design seminars -- preparatory work and materials (folder 3 of 3), ca. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Ironic Los Angeles Artist" seminar -- preparatory materials (folder 1 of 2), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Includes copy of article written about the seminar
  - "The Ironic Los Angeles Artist" seminar -- preparatory materials (folder 2 of 2), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence with Terry Allen
  - "The Ironic Los Angeles Artist" seminar -- photographs and contact sheets (folder 1 of 2), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes images of L.A. Fine Arts Squad, Bruce Nauman, Ed Ruscha, Gabrielson and other participants
  - "The Ironic Los Angeles Artist" seminar -- photographs and contact sheets (folder 2 of 2), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pop Dawson documentation, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Includes ephemera surrounding the pseudonym under which Gabrielson sometimes made work
  - Promotional materials, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chouinard Art Institute materials, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Includes correspondence regarding the exhibition, "Chouinard: fifty years of Los Angeles Art"
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- photographs, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- visual materials, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Includes slides of work exhibited and film negatives
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- preparatory work, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Includes correspondence and grant applications
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- background information, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- press release materials, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- letters from addicts, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- legal materials, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- notes on each artist, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- diagrams and logo, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- catalog essays, ca. 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Includes drafts of Gabrielson's and Ed Wortz's essays for the exhibition catalog
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- individual artist files (folder 1 of 4), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- individual artist files (folder 2 of 4), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- individual artist files (folder 3 of 4), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "Addictions" exhibition -- individual artist files (folder 4 of 4), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Addictions II -- correspondence regarding a sequel exhibition, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Ephemera from early exhibitions (folder 1 of 2), 1969-1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Includes correspondence, exhibition announcements and advertisements
  - Ephemera from early exhibitions (folder 2 of 2), 1969-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Includes correspondence as Pop Dawson
  - Press releases and materials produced by galleries, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Orr High School yearbook, 1953 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Williamson, Robert. Bits of Business., 1977 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    Artists' book given to Gabrielson
- 2. Writings and books, ca. 1960-2005
  Consists of written works and drafts.
  - Copies of published articles authored by Gabrielson, after 1981 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Early drafts for autobiography, ca. 1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Drafts of writings on art, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Drafts and revisions of short writings with drawings, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Hoax recommendation letters written with Peter Plagens, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - "Another God" rock opera -- research, ca. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Includes clippings and sketches
  - "Another God" rock opera -- drafts of scenes, ca. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Another God" rock opera -- sketches, ca. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Another God" rock opera -- script and lyrics, ca. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Past writing [sic] notebook, ca. 1975-1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Notes binder -- Celestine Prophecy, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Includes hand written thoughts on Gabrielson's experience as a reviewer and an artist being reviewed
  - Notes binder -- quotes and lessons, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Notes binder -- the artist, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Includes an interview where Gabrielson interviews himself
  - Notes binder -- philosophy, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Notes binder -- autobiography, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Notes binder -- various drafts, ca. 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Includes several pieces written in the voice of fictional television personalities, notes with sketches for the Small Town series
  - Willy drafts, 1976-1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Includes drafts of fictional correspondence
  - Zlotnik -- hoax newsletter, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Doctor book drafts and sketches, ca. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Art philosophies, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Includes tenure review and application
  - Published writings (folder 1 of 2), 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Published writings (folder 2 of 2), 1974-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Decade essay/Why Suck [sic], 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Includes work for and copy of: Gabrielson, Walter. "Why Suck the Mainstream if You Don't Live in New York." Art in America vol. 62 (January 1974): 37-8. and Gabrielson, Walter. "Narrative/Humanist Painting in Los Angeles in the Seventies." Decade: Los Angeles Painting in the Seventies.( Art Center College of Design: Pasadena, CA, 1981), 30-36.
  - Connor Everts, ca. 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Includes exhibition catalogs for Everts
  - Humor and art, ca. 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Includes various clippings, notes on Andy Kaufmann and William Wegman, and memorial booklet for Richard Dehr
  - Treiman, Woeffer, and Garabedian (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Treiman, Woeffer, and Garabedian (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hawaii writings -- drafts and source material, 1979-1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hawaii writings -- "Ocena Journal", 1979 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Includes a personal narrative with original drawings about Gabrielson's time in Hawaii
  - Stories, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Art education -- drafts and source material, ca. 2002 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - The Gig [sic], undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes an autobiographical account of Gabrielson's experience playing with a jazz band
  - Musings for autobiography [sic], ca. 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence with Peter Plagens
  - Autobiographical ephemera, 1943-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Includes childhood drawings, childhood writings, report cards, awards, and Tamarind chop definitions
  - Second edition of autobiography (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes many unordered but numbered pages with images of a near final draft of Gabrielson's autobiography
  - Second edition of autobiography (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Copies of drawings for autobiography, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Autobiography -- drawings for cover, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 1, Orr, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Includes drafts, drawings, and photographs pertaining to childhood
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 2, UCLA, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 3, UAF, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Includes photograph of Gabrielson during service in the U.S. Air Force
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 4, art school, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Includes photographs from printmaking studio
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 5, CSUN, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Includes photographs of studio in Pasadena, Betty Fiske and Peter Plagens
  - Autobiography draft -- chapters 6, the 70s (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Includes various photographs of Gabrielson and drawings
  - Autobiography draft -- chapters 6, the 70s (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes text for chapters and drawings
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 7, teaching, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Includes professional correspondence with colleges and photograph of Gabrielson
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 8 (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Includes original drawings
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 8 (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Includes photographs of Gabrielson's work, Karl Bornstein and others
  - Autobiography draft -- chapter 9, ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Includes photographs and original drawings
  - Autobiography draft -- appendix, aviation (folder 1 of 3), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Autobiography draft -- appendix, aviation (folder 2 of 3), ca. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Autobiography draft -- appendix, aviation (folder 3 of 3), ca. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Includes final revision and photographs
  - Autobiography -- aviation ephemera (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Includes images of Gabrielson and his airplanes and gliders
  - Autobiography -- aviation ephemera (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Includes original drawings of airplanes and photographs
  - Autobiography -- Orr source materials and draft, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Includes slides and maps of Orr, MN
  - Autobiography -- Orr source materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Includes photographs of Orr, MN and Gabrielson's high school class
  - Autobiography -- visual materials (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Includes photographs from various times in Gabrielson's life and original drawings
  - Autobiography -- visual materials (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Autobiography -- visual materials (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Autobiography -- Daily Bruin clippings, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Autobiography -- Images of Betty, Joyce Trieman, and Clyde, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Autobiography -- Images of UCLA, Karl Bornstein, Openings, Jose, Kessler, ca. 1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Persistence notebook -- chapter 1 draft, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Persistence notebook -- chapter 5 and portions of chapter 8 drafts, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Persistence notebook -- drafts regarding being an artist, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Persistence notebook -- portion of final draft, ca. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Persistence notebook -- revision of chapter 5, ca. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Persistence notebook -- revision of chapter 7, ca. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Persistence notebook -- revision chapters 8, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Persistence notebook -- revisions chapters 6-8, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Publishing materials, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Includes Smithsonian acquisition announcement for Gabrielson's autobiography
  - Scandinavia, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Includes original drawings and writing about personal trip to Scandinavia and photograph of Nancy Goldberg
  - Italy, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Includes original drawings and writing about personal trip to Italy
  - Television essay, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Permanent echo, ca. 1960 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    Humorous newsletter produced by Gabrielson during his time serving in the U.S. Air Force. In oversize box.
- 3. Artwork, ca. 1975-2008
  Consists primarily of preparatory work for paintings and sculptures including sketches and reference materials. In addition to preparing for Gabrielson's artwork, much of the material documents vernacular architecture and life in Southern California.
  - 2001 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Includes drawings, source material and correspondence
  - 2001 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 2000 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 1 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 2000 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 2 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 2000 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1999 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 1 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 1999 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 2 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 1999 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 1998 completed works -- preparatory materials (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1997 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 1997 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1996 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 1 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 1996 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 2 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 1996 completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 1 of 3), undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 2 of 3), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Completed works -- preparatory materials (folder 3 of 3), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Completed works -- preparatory drawings (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Completed works -- preparatory drawings (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Airplanes -- visual reference and drawings, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Airplanes -- photographs, plans, and drawings, ca. 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Airplanes -- drawings, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Angels -- drawings (folder 1 of 2), 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Angels -- drawings (folder 2 of 2), 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Angels -- visual reference, 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Angels -- photocopies of sketches, 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Angels -- preparatory drawings, ca. 1995 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Art stripped bare -- text, ca. 1998 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Consists of text portions and photocopies of the Art Stripped Bare project with Peter Plagens Gabrielson, Walter and Peter Plagens. "Art Stripped Bare." Art and Auction vol. 21 no. 8 (1998-99): 60-63.
  - Art stripped bare -- preliminary pencil drawings, ca. 1998 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Art stripped bare -- original drawings, ca. 1998 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Bakersfield -- photographic studies and drawings, ca. 1997 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Bakersfield -- photographic studies (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1997 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Bakersfield -- photographic studies (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1997 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Baseball -- Take me out to the ball game drafts (folder 1 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Includes original drawings for illustrated book of "Take me out to the ball game" song
  - Baseball -- Take me out to the ball game drafts (folder 2 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Baseball -- Take me out to the ball game drafts (folder 3 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Baseball -- Take me out to the ball game drafts (folder 4 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Baseball -- preliminary sketches for completed work (folder 1 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Includes studies for both the "Take me out to the ball game" and futurist baseball series
  - Baseball -- preliminary sketches for completed work (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Baseball -- sketches (folder 1 of 2), ca.1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Baseball -- sketches (folder 2 of 2), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Baseball -- drawings and visual reference (folder 1 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Baseball -- drawings and visual reference (folder 2 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Baseball -- drawings and visual reference (folder 3 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Baseball -- drawings and visual reference (folder 4 of 4), ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Baseball -- studies of single players, ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Baseball -- catcher visual reference, ca. 1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)